

Jake PrestonFull Stack Developer

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer — Nashville Software School

April 2019 - October 2019 - 6 months, Nashville

Intensive full-time 6-month software development Bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects.

- Designed frontend web-applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Employed Grunt, Browserify, Eslint on several JS projects
- React.js up-to-date with all the latest tooling (hooks, router, components, redux, context API, resuable API, etc.)
- Built Application Program Interfaces, Console Applications, and Model View Controls using C# .NET and Azure Data Studio.

Free Lance Infographic Designer — Tennessee Trade Association

October 2018 - January 2019 - 4 months, Nashville

- Utilized graphics to enhance patterns and trends regarding legislation
- Applied statistics and data analysis methods within the field of law
- Acted with the Association to pass bills through the Tennessee General Assembly

Fitness Instructor — Climb Nashville

February 2017 - August 2018 - 1 year, Nashville

- Instructed and mentored indoor climbing, belaying, and safety procedures to customers of all ages
- Reviewed gym operations and ensured space was kept clean
- Provided customer service and proactively sold equipment, memberships, and gear

Kitchen Manager — Sloco

February 2016 - July 2017 - 2 years, Nashville

- Held management position directing and supervising a team of 6 10 kitchen staff
- Ensured smooth operations by overseeing daily product inventory and purchasing
- Prepared meals in high volume with precision and attention to dietary restrictions
- Bartended and monitored customer experience

GROUP PROJECTS / CONTRIBUTIONS

Name	Role	Tech Stack
Nutshell	Team Lead / JavaScript Dev.	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Grunt, Browserify
Nutshell 2.0	React Developer	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js
Welcome to Nashville	JavaScript Developer	HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Trestlebridge Farms	Console-App Developer	C#
Bangazon Inc.	Full Stack Developer	C# , .NET, Entity, Identity
Bangazon WorkForce	Full Stack Developer	C# , .NET, Entity, Identity
Strabo	Full Stack Developer	Meteor.js (React, Node.js MongoDB), Figma
Climbr	Full Stack Developer	Ruby, Sinatra, React, Figma
StoryBrand	Full Stack Developer	PHP, Docker, Heroku, WordPress

CONTACT — Nashville, TN 615-512-0998 prestonjak@outlook.com jakepreston.dev linkedin.com/in/preston-jake github.com/Preston-Jake

ABOUT ME

I have carried a passion for science and technology throughout my whole life. Software Development is a way for me to combine logic with creativity and work in an industry with endless learning opportunities. I'm enthusiastic about creating interactive experiences, problem-solving, and working with teammates to develop software that is functional and sleek in design.

INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

Object-Oriented Programing
Object-Oriented Design
S.O.L.I.D Principles
Algorithms
Data Structures
Databases
Basics of Testing
User Interface
Interactive Design
Wireframing
Source Control
Software Development Life Cycle

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Node.js, Ruby, PHP, SQL

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Terminal, SSH, Git, Github, React.js, .NET, Entity, Identity, Meteor.js, MongoDB, Orchestra, Laravel, Lumen, Wordpress, Docker, CircleCi, Heroku, Azure, Azure Data Studio (MySQL), Postgres SQL, Grunt, Eslint, Browserify, JSON Server, BootStrap, ReactStrap, Material Ui

EDUCATION

Software Development Self Study - 2020 Nashville Software School - 2019 The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga - 2015

PORTFOLIO / INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS —

WWW.JAKEPRESTON.DEV